Hello, everyone, and welcome to
English Mod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine, and
today we're talking about a
very, very important part
of conversations in English.
That's right. Today we are introducing
a new series, all about small talk.
Okay, what is small talk, Marco?
Well, small talk is just
everyday conversation
about maybe the
weather, about how you are,
what's new in your life, et cetera.
It's just plain conversation.
So something very simple
and usually pretty quick.
It's what you say to people when you bump
into them, or when you see them at a party.
So let's take a listen
to today's dialogue and
find out just what kind
of small talk we have.
Hey, Michelle. This is my friend James.
He's visiting Shanghai from New York.
Oh hi, James. Nice to meet you. So, um, are
you visiting for a business or a pleasure?
Well, actually a little of both.
I'm meeting some business
contacts, but I'm also taking
some Mandarin classes, too.
Oh, that's cool. How's it going?
Well, I'm finding the class
is pretty tough, actually.
But I'm having a great time in Shanghai.
It's really an amazing city.
It sure is. Are you staying for long?
Only two weeks, unfortunately.
I wish I could stay longer, but...
Well, listen, if you need someone to
show you the sights, then just call me.
I'm having a little get-together
at my new apartment
next week, so if you
want to drop by then...
That sounds great. I'd love to.
Let me take down your number, Michelle.
All right, we're back. So now
let's take a look at a lot of great
phrases that we've picked out
for you this time on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
All right, so we've got two
Fluency Builders today, so
we're going to be exploring
a lot of different phrases.
We've got three now. The
first one is very, very common.
You hear this phrase,
"nice to meet you.
" Right, so obviously if you meet
someone new, you're introduced by
your friend or something, you
can just say, "Hi, nice to meet you."
All right, so nice to meet
you, nice to meet you, too.
That's what we say
afterwards, because it
sounds very funny if
you say it two times, so...
Hi, nice to meet you.
Oh, it's nice to meet you, too.
Right, exactly. So she
went on this girl, Michelle, to
ask if he is visiting Shanghai
for business or pleasure.
All right, this is an
important difference,
something that we often
talk about in Small Talk.
You can travel for business,
that means business trips.
You can travel to see different sites
and have fun that's called pleasure.
And so we often hear this phrase, "business
or pleasure." Right, so if someone
comes to your country, you say, "Oh,
sorry, you hear for business or pleasure.
" Oh, I'm here on business, or I'm
here to see the sites. Okay, very good.
And so James is actually in
Shanghai doing both things.
He's on a business trip, but
he's also taking Mandarin classes.
And so Michelle went on to
say, "That's great. How's it going?
" All right, you're going to
hear this all the time in English.
We say, "How's it going
to our friends and family?"
I wouldn't say it in a formal occasion
with my boss or with my teacher,
but it's very casual, very informal,
and it's a way to ask how things are.
Right.
So you're taking classes? How's it going?
Mm-hmm, exactly. So
this basically means, "How
are the classes going?
How is everything?"
Right, or you could say, "Oh,
Marco, I haven't seen you in a while.
How is it going?"
Uh-huh, and that's another way of saying
hi to someone or saying, "How are you?"
How are you? How have you been recently?
So there are two differences
in that phrase there.
In this case, Michelle is asking, "How
the Mandarin classes are going? How is it?
" "Is it good? Is it bad? Is it
difficult? Is it easy, et cetera?
" But if you say to
someone, "Hi, I haven't seen
you for such a long
time. How's it going?
" That's more of a
"How are you" type thing.
That's like how's your life going.
Exactly. So just think about
what you're talking about.
Are you talking about general
situations, like your person's life?
Or are you talking about
maybe lessons or class or job?
That's right.
Okay, so we're going to take a break here.
Let's listen to the
dialogue again and we'll
be back in a little
bit with more phrases.
Hey, Michelle. This is my friend James.
He's visiting Shanghai from New York.
Oh, hi, James. Nice to meet you.
So are you visiting for
a business or a pleasure?
Well, actually a little of both.
I'm meeting some business contacts,
but I'm also taking some
Mandarin classes too.
Oh, that's cool. How's it going?
Well, I'm finding the class
is pretty tough, actually.
But I'm having a great time in Shanghai.
It's really an amazing city.
It sure is. Are you staying for long?
Only two weeks, unfortunately.
I wish I could stay longer, but...
Well, listen, if you need someone to
show you the sites, then just call me.
I'm having a little get-together
at my new apartment next week.
So if you want to drop by then...
That sounds great. I'd love to.
Let me take down your number, Michelle.
All right, we're back, so now let's
take a look at Fluency Builder Part 2.
So, Michelle at the end
of today's dialogue says,
"If you need someone to show
you the sites, then just call me.
" All right, so to show
someone the sites,
we talked about this a little bit
earlier with that word "pleasure."
What does it mean to show
someone the site's Marco?
So, basically, the sites
we're talking about
the different attractions
of a city or place.
So, the museums may be different buildings
or different attractions in general.
What is there to site see?
Okay, so we're in Paris, Marco, and I
say, "Hey, I'd love to show you the sites.
What do you expect to see?
" So, maybe we would go to the
Eiffel Tower, maybe we would go to...
Notre Dame Cathedral.
Exactly.
So, we would go see
all these different sites.
And to show, and that would
mean that you are showing
me the sites, you are taking
me to see all these sites.
Okay.
And she is also having a little get-together
at her apartment, at her new apartment.
So, what is a little get-together?
This is a noun.
This is a get-together,
so think about this.
Two different words actually get
together, but it's a noun, it's a thing.
It's like a party, but it's a small party.
Right.
A little get-together.
So, I like to think of a
get-together as something
very casual, something very
small, sometimes intimate.
Well, you just have three
or four or five friends.
It's not as big as a party
where everyone's dancing.
Right.
Okay.
So, a little get-together is
just a small group of people.
You invite them over to your house.
Very relaxed, very casual.
It's not really a party.
It's more of a re-union of friends.
And, like we said, it's a noun.
So, you say, I'm having a get-together.
You should come.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
And she actually asks him to come,
but she says it in a different way.
She says, if you want to drop by.
Okay.
This is something people
often say in small talk,
because you don't want to say
you should come stay for a while.
Because that's, I don't know.
They just met.
It's not an order.
So, you should drop by means you should
come and see and decide if you want to stay.
So, basically, it's also kind
of a relaxed way of saying,
"You can come whenever you want
during our party or get-together.
" So, if the
get-together is 9 p.m.
to midnight, you can drop by
whenever 10 o'clock, 11 o'clock.
So, to drop by is to
come for a short period.
So, if we're talking
on the phone and I say,
"I'll drop by your
house later on today.
" That means I'm going to go to your
house very quickly at an unexpected time.
Yeah, or you could have
used it in a question, you know.
Marco, I really wanted to borrow that DVD.
When can I drop by to pick it up?
Okay, very, very good.
Now, let's take a look at our last phrase.
Michelle and James decided
that they want to keep in touch.
And so, he said, "Let me
take down your number.
" Okay, so, we're not talking
about taking it anywhere.
We're taking a number
anywhere and going somewhere.
We're talking about writing something down.
So, in this case, your
number is your phone number.
Okay, let me take down your number.
It means let me write down
your telephone number.
Uh-huh.
Okay, so, it's another way of saying,
"Let me write down
your telephone number.
" Take down my phone
number, call me later.
That's right.
So, can I take down your
number so I can call you later?
Okay, that's another way
of asking this question.
Very good.
All right, so that
concludes Fluency Builder.
We'll have one last time
and we'll be back in a bit.
Hey, Michelle.
This is my friend James.
He's visiting Shanghai from New York.
Oh, hi, James. Nice to meet you.
So, um, are you visiting
for business or a pleasure?
Well, actually, a little of both.
I'm meeting some business contacts, but
I'm also taking some Mandarin classes too.
Oh, that's cool.
How's it going?
Well, I'm finding the
classes pretty tough, actually,
but I'm having a great time in Shanghai.
It's really an amazing city.
It sure is.
Are you staying for long?
Only two weeks, unfortunately.
I wish I could stay longer, but...
Well, listen, if you need someone to
show you the sights, then just call me.
I'm having a little get-together
at my new apartment next week,
so if you want to drop by
then... That sounds great.
I'd love to.
Let me take down your number, Michelle.
Okay, so this is part one
of our small talk series.
We're going to have 10
episodes, and in each episode,
we're going to be faced
with a little different situation
or circumstance where we will be forced
to have a very quick chat with someone.
That's right.
And so you're often going to
find yourself in these situations
if you're traveling to an
English-speaking country,
or you're living or working
in America, for example.
And so it's really
important because I think
oftentimes you don't
learn this in class.
This is the thing that
you have to really learn
when you're in the country or
learn with us here at English Pause.
That's right, it's a
little bit of social skills
for these awkward or
maybe new situations.
Exactly.
All right, so if you guys
have any other questions
or doubts, you can
find us at EnglishPause.
com and we'll see
everyone there.
Bye, guys!